Cordula Hansen

UX Designer and VR producer

About

Design educator with almost 15 years' experience turned UX designer and entrepreneur specialising in innovative and engaging VR content.

Contact

Dublin, Ireland +353 87 2815408 cordula@cordhan.net portfolio: www.cordhan.net

Skills

User Research Skills

Ethnography
Discourse analysis
User interviews
Usability and preference testing
Heuristic analysis
Personas
Business requirements
User flows and storyboarding
Site maps
Rapid prototyping

Tools

Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, XD Balsamiq InVision Sketch HTML5 CSS3 JavaScript Unity 3D

Project Management

Agile project management Scrum Personal Kanban Business development

Communication Skills

Writing for publication Proposal and grant writing Video editing Facilitating workshops and meetings Fluent in English and German

Experience

Cordhan Productions Ltd. (Dublin, Ireland) Founder and Director

2019-present

Founded Cordhan Productions Ltd., a design agency specialising in immersive media, such as VR, AR, XR and experiential spatial design.

Facilitates virtual reality demos, instruction and events for corporate clients. Prepares business analysis for immersive brand experiences. Conducts heuristic analysis and user research for immersive projects. Creates storyboards, 3D prototypes and complete XR experiences (portfolio).

Waterford Institute of Technology (Waterford, Ireland) Director and Principal Investigator

2016-2018

Founded and managed WIT Research Group for Design and Social Innovation (DASI) to facilitate interdisciplinary collaboration and prevent working in silos.

Won funding for a PhD scholar to be recruited for a four-year research project.

Research Supervisor and Lecturer in Design

2005-2018

Designed and delivered student-centric educational programmes from undergraduate to postgraduate level. Managed course content and weekly lectures on graphic design, research methods and business modules.

Organised and facilitated UX design summer schools for graduates, researchers, colleagues and industry collaborators to increase awareness about tech-relevant design paradigms and to integrate industry-relevant content into coursework, increasing students' employment prospects.

Education

Certificate in UX Design with Front-End Specialization (2019)

CareerFoundry

Intensive training programme for UX Designers, specializing in UX process and methodology that includes user research, user journeys, user personas, testing, information architecture and visual design fundamentals. Designed several real world projects using InVision and Adobe XD for wireframes and prototyping.

PhD in Art and Archaeology (2008)

Waterford Institute of Technology

Conducted a longitundinal ethnographic study and discourse analysis on "The Role of the Art Practitioner in Theoretical Archaeology".

Published in peer-reviewed journals and presented at international conferences.

BA(Hons) in Visual Art (2003)

Waterford Institute of Technology

Specialisations in sculpture, multimedia installation and arts management.

VR projects

Emotional Data in a Smart City - VR environment (2018)

Commissioned by Building City Dashboards Research Group, Maynooth University. Funded by Science Foundation Ireland (SFI).

PalmHouse Philosophy - VR artwork (2016-2018)

Virtual Reality Artwork Demo using Google Tiltbrush, exhibited at 404 tech meetup, Autodesk and Google Developer Group Hackathons in Dublin.